ANSAR MEMON | Full Stack Developer

+971 52 913 9295 | ansarkmemon@gmail.com | Dubai, UAE

ABOUT ME

I am a Self-taught, Full Stack Developer with +2 years of experience as an independent developer. Using my passion for programming and developing solutions, I added to the success of my clients by implementing best User Experience practices in their projects. I am hungry to collaborate and work in a team to solve bigger engineering challenges using code. I love learning new technologies and I have been able to learn extremely fast and implement the new knowledge and skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

FRONTEND TECHNOLOGIES















DESIGN TOOLS













BACKEND TECHNOLOGIES





DATABASE TECHNOLOGIES





CMS



LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

(Fluent)

HINDI

(Fluent)

MARATHI

• • 0 0

(Intermediate)

ARABIC

• • 0 0 0

(Basic)

WORK EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPER

THE RAIZULI DESIGN SERVICES

2013 - Present

Being an independent developer, I have played multiple roles as is common with any freelancer. Some of the challenges & tasks that I have enjoyed and have hands on experience with

- Working with clients to understand their needs and business challenges and to come up with creative solution.
- Educating the clients about the new technologies and their benefits for their project.
- Managing the clients and their expectations ensuring their happiness and satisfaction with my services and final product.
- Using my design skills to develop highly intuitive and modern User Interfaces while following best User Experience practices.
- Writing clean, modular and scalable code to develop the frontend and backend services or integrating with commonly use CMS technologies.
- Keeping up-to-date about the new technologies & frameworks and advicing the clients on the best technology to consider for solving their problems.
- Preparing Project Proposals, Negotiating the deals while trying to maintain the competitive edge.
- Marketing and Networking through both online and offline channels to grow the business.
- Maintaining and Monitoring proper Financial Reports and Accounts regularly to ensure smooth operations.

PRODUCT MANAGER - MEDICAL DIVISION

BDH MIDDLE EAST

2012 - 2013

• Maintaining long term customer relationships with the existing customers while developing network of new customers.

- Working closely with the suppliers and keeping them up-to-date about the sales proceeds.
- Marketing and promoting the product through presentations/demonstrations and following it through till the order is generated.
- Maintaining the database of competitors, their products and their pricing strategies.
- Identifying and participating in various regional trade shows.
- Participating and recommending the regional conferences whilst utilizing optimum level resources.
- Providing clinical training to the end users and ensuring that they are confident in using the device to treat patients.
- Identifying and developing the potential market in other GCC countries.

PRODUCT SPECIALIST - MEDICAL DIVISION

METROPOLITAN
MEDICAL MARKETING

2010 - 2012

• Experience in Marketing, Maximizing sales orders, margin, market share, customer satisfaction of given products and solutions in UAE.

- Developing good long term customer relationships, and high customer satisfaction whilst utilizing to optimum level resources in the team and Company.
- Organizing product demonstrations, site visits and follow up and establishing the new brands in the market.
- Preparing and coordinating the tender response and validating the tender documentation in collaboration with line manager.
- Generating record and maintaining customer profiles, including keeping track of key decision makers.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

MAHE MANIPAL UNIVERSITY, DUBAI

2011 - 2013

MASTERS IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION (MBA) FINANCE GRADUATE

BIRLA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, RANCHI - DUBAI CAMPUS

2006 - 2010

BACHELORS IN ENGINEERING (BE) ELECTRONICS & COMMUNICATIONS

SELF LEARNING

ONLINE



BOOKS

Javascript & JQuery - Jon Duckett

You Don't Know JS - Kyle Simpson

ng-book - The Complete Book of Angular 4

- Nate Murray
- Felipe Coury
- Ari Lerner
- Carlos Taborda

Data Structures and Algorithms with Javascript - Michael McMillan

ME ONLINE

GITHUB - github.com/amoury

WEBSITE - amourycodes.com (Under Development)

LINKEDIN - linkedin.com/in/amoury